smartwatchnews.org 2015-10-01

# Privacy Policy - Smart Watch News

Your privacy is important to SmartNews. This Privacy Policy covers how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your information. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with this Privacy Policy and let us know if you have any questions.

 **Collection and Use of Personal Information**

Personal information is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person.

You may be asked to provide your personal information anytime you are in contact with SmartNews. SmartNews may use this personal information and may also combine it with other information to provide and improve our products, services, content, and advertising.

 **What Personal Information We Collect**

When you create a user account at SmartNews we may collect a variety of information, including your name, email address, web site url, and contact preferences.

The personal information we collect allows us to keep you posted on SmartNews’s latest product announcements, software updates, and upcoming events. It also helps us to improve our services, content, and advertising. If you don’t want to be on our mailing list, you can opt out anytime by updating your preferences.

We also use personal information to help us develop, deliver, and improve our products, services, content, and advertising.

From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies. Because this information is important to your interaction with SmartNews, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.

We may also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve SmartNews’s products, services, and customer communications.

If you enter into a sweepstake, contest, or similar promotion we may use the information you provide to administer those programs.

 **Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information**

We also collect non-personal information − data in a form that does not permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it:

We may collect information such as language, location, and time zone so that we can better understand customer behavior and improve our products, services, and advertising.

 **Cookies and Other Technologies**

SmartNews’s website, online services, interactive applications, email messages, and advertisements may use “cookies” and other technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons. These technologies help us better understand user behavior, tell us which parts of our website people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

SmartNews uses cookies and other technologies in mobile advertising services to control the number of times you see a given ad, deliver ads that relate to your interests, and measure the effectiveness of ad campaigns. If you do not want to receive ads with this level of relevance on your mobile device, you can opt out. If you opt out, you will continue to receive the same number of mobile ads, but they may be less relevant because they will not be based on your interests. You may still see ads related to the content on a web page or in an application or based on other non-personal information. This opt-out applies only to SmartNews advertising services and does not affect interest-based advertising from other advertising networks.

SmartNews also uses cookies and other technologies to remember personal information when you use our website. Our goal is to make your experience with SmartNews more convenient and personal. For example, knowing your first name lets us welcome you the next time you visit our website. Knowing someone using your computer or device has shopped for a certain product or used a particular service helps us make our advertising and email communications more relevant to your interests.

As is true of most websites, we gather some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, and date/time stamp.

We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. SmartNews may use this information in our marketing and advertising services.

In some of our email messages, we use a “click-through URL” linked to content on the SmartNews website. When customers click one of these URLs, they pass through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page on our website. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text or graphic links in the email messages.

Pixel tags enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they tell us whether mail has been opened. We may use this information to reduce or eliminate messages sent to customers.

 **Third Parties**

It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence − for SmartNews to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate.

We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our operations or users.

 **Protection of Personal Information**

SmartNews takes precautions — including administrative, technical, and physical measures — to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

When you post on a SmartNews forum, chat room, or social networking service, the personal information you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these instances. For example, if you list your name and email address in a forum posting, that information is public. Please take care when using these features.

 **Integrity and Retention of Personal Information**

SmartNews makes it easy for you to keep your personal information accurate, complete, and up to date. We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

 **Access to Personal Information**

You can help ensure that your contact information and preferences are accurate, complete, and up to date by logging in to your account at SmartNews. For other personal information, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access so you can request that we correct the data if it is inaccurate or delete the data if SmartNews is not required to retain it by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Access, correction, or deletion requests can be made through the Contact Us form.

 **Children**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under 13 we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

 **Third-Party Sites and Services**

SmartNews’s websites may contain links to third-party websites, products, and services. Information collected by third parties, which may include such things as location data or contact details, is governed by their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties.

 **Our Commitment to Your Privacy**

To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate our privacy and security guidelines to SmartNews’s employees and strictly enforce privacy safeguards within the company.

 **Privacy Questions**

If you have any questions or concerns about SmartNews’s Privacy Policy or data processing, please contact us.

 **Privacy Policy Updates**

SmartNews may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy.
